JOHN CRIS TAYCO

Web Developer

ABOUT ME

Experienced Web Developer with a demonstrated history of working in frontend and backend applications. Skilled in Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), JavaScript, HTML. Expert in Coldfusion with FuseBox Framework and SQL Server. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused

CONTACT ME

Phone

+8180 7490 5132

Current Address

Tokyo, Itabashi, Oyaguchi Kitamachi 5 - 1, Oakhouse Naka itabashi 101

Home Address

B41 L8, Limestone St., Deca Homes Esperanza, Tigatto, Davao City, Davao Del Sur, Philippines

Fmail

bugz3jc@gmail.com

S live:bugz3jc

(D)

EXPERIENCE

HTML Email Developer | APRIL, 2016 - FEBRUARY 2017

AwesomeOS (OffSourcing Philippines Inc.)

- Develop HTML for e-mail marketing campaigns based on mock up design.
- Testing in various email platforms such as Gmail, Outlook, Apple Mail etc., for debugging and compatibility using Litmus.
- Testing in actual devices in mobile and desktop, and across various operating systems.

Frontend Developer (Shopify) | MARCH, 2017 - MAY 2017

Stealth Venture Labs (AwesomeOS)

- Developed and maintained frontend in websites within the Shopify Platform using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Liquid.
- Worked with Project Managers for task specifications and distributions.
- Coordinated with backend developer for data specifications.
- Worked with A/B Testing tools to determine which alternate designs and layout is

Backend Developer | JULY, 2017 - JANUARY 2020

TechStyle Fashion Group (AwesomeOS)

- Developed and Maintained web-based tools for managing contents in an F-Commerce websites
- Used HTML, CSS, JQuery for displaying data, forms and managing inputs
- Used ColdFusion with FuseBox framework as a main programming language for processing and communicating data to the database.
- Develop and update existing SQL Stored Procedure scripts for fetching and storing data in the database using SQL Server.
- Provided Technical solutions as described by task requirements.
- Addressed technical queries from users.
- Worked with QA team for testing and debugging.

IT Engineer | JANUARY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020

TechnoPro Engineering Inc, Tokyo, Japan

- Attended trainings on Python and PHP programing languages through WinSchool.

EDUCATION

JUNE 2012 - APRIL 2016

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

University of Mindanao

Davao City, Davao Del Sur, Philippines

SKILLS

Visual Studio Code

Technical Personal Softwares HTML, CSS Teamwork Git JQuery, Reactjs Innovative SourceTree

PHP, Codelgniter Learner Resourceful ColdFusion Python

MySQL SQL Server

Spoken Language

Filipino English Japanese (basic) Others

Photography